Guide to the Robert Maynard Hutchins Papers 1884-2000
University of Chicago Library
- Series VI: Encyclopædia Britannica
  - Subseries 1: General
    - Great Ideas Today - "The Great Anti-School Campaign," Robert M. Hutchins, circa 1972 (Box 268, Folder 2)
    - Great Ideas Today - "The Great Anti-School Campaign," Robert M. Hutchins, circa 1972 (Box 268, Folder 3)
    - Great Ideas Today - "The Great Anti-School Campaign," Robert M. Hutchins [1/3], circa 1971-1972 (Box 268, Folder 4)
    - Great Ideas Today - "The Great Anti-School Campaign," Robert M. Hutchins [2/3], circa 1971-1972 (Box 268, Folder 5)
    - Great Ideas Today - "The Great Anti-School Campaign," Robert M. Hutchins [3/3], circa 1971-1972 (Box 268, Folder 6)
    - Great Ideas Today - "The Great Anti-School Campaign," Robert M. Hutchins, 1972 (Box 268, Folder 7)
    - Great Treasury of Western Thought, 1976-1977 (Box 268, Folder 8)
    - "How the New Britannica Came to Be," Robert M. Hutchins, undated (Box 269, Folder 1)
    - Institute of Philosophical Research study, 1960 (Box 269, Folder 2)
    - Know magazine, Spring 1968 (Box 269, Folder 3)
    - Know magazine, Summer 1968 (Box 269, Folder 4)
    - Plan B - Memorandum, Warren Preece, 1969 (Box 269, Folder 5)
    - Public relations, 1964-1968 (Box 269, Folder 6)
    - Reference index entries, undated (Box 269, Folder 7)
    - REP classified lists, 1963 (Box 269, Folder 8)
    - Soviet Education - Publications about, 1958-1961 (Box 269, Folder 9)
    - Study guides, 1961 (Box 269, Folder 10)
    - Table of contents essay invitees - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 269, Folder 11)
    - The Time of Our Lives - Lectures, 1968 (Box 270, Folder 1)
    - Trip to Japan, 1967-1968 (Box 270, Folder 2)
    - "What I Believe," Pearl S. Buck, undated (Box 270, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 2: Correspondence
    - General, 1959 (Box 270, Folder 4)
    - General, November-December, 1958 (Box 270, Folder 5)
    - General, August-October, 1958 (Box 270, Folder 6)
    - General, June-July, 1958 (Box 270, Folder 7)
    - General, March-May, 1958 (Box 270, Folder 8)
    - General, January-February, 1958 (Box 270, Folder 9)
    - General, November-December, 1957 (Box 270, Folder 10)
    - General, April-October, 1957 (Box 271, Folder 1)
    - General, January-May, 1957 (Box 271, Folder 2)
    - General, 1955-1956 (Box 271, Folder 3)
    - General - A-E, 1960-1975 (Box 271, Folder 4)
    - Adler, Mortimer J., 1966-1967 (Box 271, Folder 5)
    - Adler, Mortimer J., 1967-1970 (Box 271, Folder 6)
    - Adler, Mortimer J., 1972 (Box 271, Folder 7)
    - Adler, Mortimer J., 1973 (Box 271, Folder 8)
    - Adler, Mortimer J. - "Some Questions About Language" [1/2], 1973 (Box 272, Folder 1)
    - Adler, Mortimer J. - "Some Questions About Language" [2/2], 1973 (Box 272, Folder 2)
    - Adler, Mortimer J., 1974 (Box 272, Folder 3)
    - Annals of America, 1969 (Box 272, Folder 4)
    - Armitage, John, 1960-1967 (Box 272, Folder 5)
    - Armstrong, Paul T., 1966-1974 (Box 272, Folder 6)
    - Ashmore, Harry, 1966-1967 (Box 272, Folder 7)
    - General - B, 1957-1976 (Box 272, Folder 8)
    - Barnes, John - Correspondence [1/2], 1960-1973 (Box 272, Folder 9)
    - Barnes, John - Correspondence [2/2], 1962-1966 (Box 273, Folder 1)
    - Barzun, Jacques - "Notes on the making of an Encyclopædia," 1960-1962 (Box 273, Folder 2)
    - Benton, Charles [1/2], 1960-1976 (Box 273, Folder 3)
    - Benton, Charles [2/2], 1962-1966 (Box 273, Folder 4)
    - Benton, William, January-June 1966 (Box 273, Folder 5)
    - Benton, William, July-December 1966 (Box 273, Folder 6)
    - Benton, William, January-June 1967 (Box 274, Folder 1)
    - Benton, William, July-December 1967 (Box 274, Folder 2)
    - Benton, William, January-June 1968 (Box 274, Folder 3)
    - Benton, William, July-December 1968 (Box 274, Folder 4)
    - Benton, William, January-March 1969 (Box 274, Folder 5)
    - Benton, William, April-June 1969 (Box 274, Folder 6)
    - Benton, William, July-December 1969 (Box 274, Folder 7)
    - Benton, William, January-February 1970 (Box 275, Folder 1)
    - Benton, William, March-June 1970 (Box 275, Folder 2)
    - Benton, William, February-December 1970 (Box 275, Folder 3)
    - Benton, William, January-June 1971 (Box 275, Folder 4)
    - Benton, William, July-November 1971 (Box 275, Folder 5)
    - Benton, William, December 1971 (Box 275, Folder 6)
    - Benton, William, January-March 1972 (Box 275, Folder 7)
    - Benton, William, April-June 1972 (Box 276, Folder 1)
    - Benton, William, July-December 1972 (Box 276, Folder 2)
    - General, C, 1956-1959 (Box 276, Folder 3)
    - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, 1960 (Box 276, Folder 4)
    - Chicago, 1959 (Box 276, Folder 5)
    - Chicago and New York, 1959 (Box 276, Folder 6)
    - Collins, George, 1964-1976 (Box 276, Folder 7)
    - Conger, Robert A., 1960-1963 (Box 276, Folder 8)
    - Cousins, Norman, 1959-1969 (Box 276, Folder 9)
    - Cronin, Anne, 1960-1971 (Box 276, Folder 10)
    - Crowther, Sir Geoffrey, 1958-1972 (Box 276, Folder 11)
    - Curtis, Thomas B., 1970-1973 (Box 277, Folder 1)
    - Dodge, John V., 1960-1968 (Box 277, Folder 2)
    - General - E, 1959 (Box 277, Folder 3)
    - Feldzamen, A. N., 1969-1971 (Box 277, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence - G, 1951-1976 (Box 277, Folder 5)
    - Garner, Mary Kate, 1962-1969 (Box 277, Folder 6)
    - Gibney, Frank [1/2], 1972-1976 (Box 277, Folder 7)
    - Gibney, Frank [2/2], 1967-1973 (Box 277, Folder 8)
    - Goodkind, Howard L., 1966-1972 (Box 277, Folder 9)
    - Gwinn, Robert P. [1/2], 1973-1977 (Box 277, Folder 10)
    - Gwinn, Robert P. [2/2], 1973-1974 (Box 278, Folder 1)
    - General - H, 1944-1969 (Box 278, Folder 2)
    - Haley, Sir William [1/2], 1968-1977 (Box 278, Folder 3)
    - Haley, Sir William [2/2], 1962-1969 (Box 278, Folder 4)
    - Hazo, Robert, 1970-1974 (Box 278, Folder 5)
    - Joy, Harry J. [1/2], 1973-1977 (Box 278, Folder 6)
    - Joy, Harry J. [2/2], 1961-1973 (Box 278, Folder 7)
    - General - K, 1967-1969 (Box 278, Folder 8)
    - Kogan, Herman, 1960-1972 (Box 278, Folder 9)
    - General - L, 1951-1970 (Box 278, Folder 10)
    - London and Canada, 1959 (Box 278, Folder 11)
    - General - M-Z [1/2], 1947-1975 (Box 279, Folder 1)
    - General - M-Z [2/2], 1960-1976 (Box 279, Folder 2)
    - Praeger, Frederick A., 1966-1977 (Box 279, Folder 3)
    - Preble, Robert C., 1951-1956 (Box 279, Folder 4)
    - Preece, Warren [1/4], 1971-1977 (Box 279, Folder 5)
    - Preece, Warren [2/4], 1968-1974 (Box 279, Folder 6)
    - Preece, Warren [3/4], 1971-1973 (Box 279, Folder 7)
    - Preece, Warren [4/4], 1962-1971 (Box 280, Folder 1)
    - Queneau, Raymond - "Prospectus for the Encyclopædia of the Pléiade," 1964-1965 (Box 280, Folder 2)
    - Richards, Howard, 1965-1966 (Box 280, Folder 3)
    - Robling, John [1/2], 1971-1976 (Box 280, Folder 4)
    - Robling, John [2/2], 1967-1970 (Box 280, Folder 5)
    - Swanson, Charles [1/2], 1969-1976 (Box 280, Folder 6)
    - Swanson, Charles [2/2], 1967-1969 (Box 280, Folder 7)
    - Table of Intents - Editorial Guide, 1968 (Box 280, Folder 8)
    - Ulam, Stanislaw M., 1965 (Box 281, Folder 1)
    - Van Doren, Charles, 1960-1975 (Box 281, Folder 2)
    - Van Doren, Charles, 1960 (Box 281, Folder 3)
    - Wheeler, Harvey, 1962-1966 (Box 281, Folder 4)
    - Wheeler, Harvey [1/2], 1965-1966 (Box 281, Folder 5)
    - Wheeler, Harvey [2/2], 1963-1965 (Box 281, Folder 6)
    - Wilkinson, John, 1962-1965 (Box 281, Folder 7)
    - Wittlin, Alma S., 1964 (Box 281, Folder 8)
    - Woetzel, Robert K., 1964-1965 (Box 281, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 3: Board of Editors
    - Board of Editors, 1952-1959 (Box 282, Folder 1)
    - Membership, 1957-1968 (Box 282, Folder 2)
    - Long-term planning, 1960 (Box 282, Folder 3)
    - To Advance Knowledge - Book about Board of Editors, 1962 (Box 282, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1975 (Box 282, Folder 5)
    - Photographs, circa 1961-1975 (Box 282, Folder 6)
    - Meeting, October 1959 (Box 282, Folder 7)
    - Meeting, October 1960 (Box 282, Folder 8)
    - Meeting, January 1961 (Box 283, Folder 1)
    - Meeting, January 1961 - Papers (Box 283, Folder 2)
    - Meeting, April 1961 (Box 283, Folder 3)
    - Meeting, April 1961 - Papers (Box 283, Folder 4)
    - Meeting, June 1961 (Box 283, Folder 5)
    - Meeting, June 1961 - Papers (Box 284, Folder 1)
    - Meeting, October 1961 - Memoranda and working paper (Box 284, Folder 2)
    - Meeting, October 1961 (Box 284, Folder 3)
    - Meetings, January 1962 [1/2] (Box 284, Folder 4)
    - Meetings, January 1962 [2/2] (Box 284, Folder 5)
    - Meetings, January 1962 - Papers (Box 284, Folder 6)
    - Meetings, April 1962 (Box 284, Folder 7)
    - Meetings, April 1962 - Papers (Box 285, Folder 1)
    - Meetings, June 1962 (Box 285, Folder 2)
    - Meetings, October 1962 (Box 285, Folder 3)
    - Meetings, October 1962 - Papers [1/2] (Box 285, Folder 4)
    - Meetings, October 1962 - Papers [2/2] (Box 285, Folder 5)
    - Meetings, January 1963 (Box 285, Folder 6)
    - Meetings, January 1963 - Papers (Box 286, Folder 1)
    - Meetings, April 1963 (Box 286, Folder 2)
    - Meetings, April 1963 - Papers (Box 286, Folder 3)
    - Meetings, June 1963 - Not held (Box 286, Folder 4)
    - Meetings, November 1963 (Box 286, Folder 5)
    - Meetings, November 1963 [1/4] (Box 286, Folder 6)
    - Meetings, November 1963 [2/4] (Box 287, Folder 1)
    - Meetings, November 1963 [3/4] (Box 287, Folder 2)
    - Meetings, November 1963 [4/4] (Box 287, Folder 3)
    - Meetings, 1963-1964 (Box 287, Folder 4)
    - Meetings, April 1964 (Box 287, Folder 5)
    - Meetings, June 1964 (Box 287, Folder 6)
    - Britannica planning - Special meeting, September 1964 (Box 287, Folder 7)
    - Meeting, 1964 (Box 288, Folder 1)
    - Meeting, October 1964 (Box 288, Folder 2)
    - Meeting, 1964-1965 (Box 288, Folder 3)
    - Meeting, 1965 (Box 288, Folder 4)
    - Meeting, 1966 (Box 288, Folder 5)
    - Meeting, 1968 (Box 288, Folder 6)
    - Meeting, 1969 (Box 288, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 4: Content Development
    - Phase II - History, early activity reports, 1960-1961 (Box 288, Folder 8)
    - Phase II, 1961-1964 (Box 288, Folder 9)
    - Phase II - Clifton Fadiman, 1963-1964 (Box 288, Folder 10)
    - Phase II - Planning Committee, 1963-1964 (Box 288, Folder 11)
    - Conference on the Technological Order, 1962 (Box 288, Folder 12)
    - Conference - Second Corning, 1962 (Box 288, Folder 13)
    - Conference - Legal Order, 1962 (Box 288, Folder 14)
    - Conference - Science and Technology, 1962-1963 (Box 288, Folder 15)
    - Conference - Florence, June 29-July 3, 1964 (Box 289, Folder 1)
    - "Nature" - Roof article and conference [1/3], 1964 (Box 289, Folder 2)
    - "Nature" - Roof article and conference [2/3], 1964 (Box 289, Folder 3)
    - "Nature" - Roof article and conference [3/3], 1964 (Box 289, Folder 4)
    - Roof article conference, Santa Barbara - Minutes, October 9-12, 1964 (Box 289, Folder 5)
    - Roof article conference, Santa Barbara - Summary and minutes, June 11-12, 1965 (Box 289, Folder 6)
    - "Britannica Perspectives," 1968 (Box 289, Folder 7)
    - "Britannica Perspectives" - "Gendaijin No Kyoyo" - Reviews, 1968 (Box 289, Folder 8)
    - Roof article - General Correspondence, A-G, 1960-1964 (Box 289, Folder 9)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Adler, Mortimer J. [1/2], 1966 (Box 290, Folder 1)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Adler, Mortimer J. [2/2], 1962-1964 (Box 290, Folder 2)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Aron, Raymond, 1964-1967 (Box 290, Folder 3)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Ashmore, Harry [1/3], 1966-1967 (Box 290, Folder 4)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Ashmore, Harry [2/3], 1963-1967 (Box 290, Folder 5)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Ashmore, Harry [3/3], 1961-1963 (Box 290, Folder 6)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Bailey, Eugene, 1962-1966 (Box 290, Folder 7)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Black, Max, 1965-1966 (Box 291, Folder 1)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Barr, Stringfellow, 1967 (Box 291, Folder 2)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Borgese, Elisabeth, 1963-1966 (Box 291, Folder 3)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Cain, Seymour [1/2], 1964-1967 (Box 291, Folder 4)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Cain, Seymour [2/2], 1964-1965 (Box 291, Folder 5)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Calder, Ritchie [1/3], 1964-1967 (Box 291, Folder 6)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Calder, Ritchie [2/3], 1965 (Box 291, Folder 7)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Calder, Ritchie [3/3], 1965 (Box 292, Folder 1)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Cogley, John, 1962-1966 (Box 292, Folder 2)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Dubos, René [1/3], 1966 (Box 292, Folder 3)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Dubos, René [2/3], 1966 (Box 292, Folder 4)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Dubos, René [3/3], 1964-1967 (Box 292, Folder 5)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Fadman, Clifton [1/4], 1965-1969 (Box 292, Folder 6)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Fadman, Clifton [2/4], 1963-1965 (Box 292, Folder 7)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Fadman, Clifton [3/4], 1963 (Box 293, Folder 1)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Fadman, Clifton [4/4], 1962-1965 (Box 293, Folder 2)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Forbes, Robert J. [1/3], undated (Box 293, Folder 3)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Forbes, Robert J. [2/3], undated (Box 293, Folder 4)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Forbes, Robert J. [3/3], 1964-1968 (Box 293, Folder 5)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Fuller, Lon [1/3], 1963-1966 (Box 293, Folder 6)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Fuller, Lon [2/3], 1963-1964 (Box 293, Folder 7)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Fuller, Lon [3/3], 1962-1963 (Box 294, Folder 1)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - General Correspondence, H-O, 1962-1965 (Box 294, Folder 2)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Hazo, Robert, 1965 (Box 294, Folder 3)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Robert M. Hutchins, Education, 1962-1963 (Box 294, Folder 4)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Robert M. Hutchins, Education [1/2], 1965 (Box 294, Folder 5)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Robert M. Hutchins, Education [2/2], 1962-1967 (Box 294, Folder 6)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Robert M. Hutchins, Education, 1965-1966 (Box 295, Folder 1)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Robert M. Hutchins, "Issues in Education" - Final draft, 1966 (Box 295, Folder 2)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Robert M. Hutchins, "Issues in Education" - Final draft, 1966 (Box 295, Folder 3)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Robert M. Hutchins, "Issues in Education" - Final draft, undated (Box 295, Folder 4)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Robert M. Hutchins, Education, notes, 1966-1967 (Box 295, Folder 5)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Iyer, Raghavan, 1963-1965 (Box 295, Folder 6)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions -Kac, Mark, 1964-1966 (Box 295, Folder 7)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Keegan, Frank [1/3], 1965-1971 (Box 295, Folder 8)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Keegan, Frank [2/3], 1964-1965 (Box 296, Folder 1)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Keegan, Frank [3/3], 1964 (Box 296, Folder 2)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - McKeon, Richard P., 1954-1964 (Box 296, Folder 3)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - McMullen, Roy [1/2], 1965-1966 (Box 296, Folder 4)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - McMullen, Roy [2/2], 1963-1966 (Box 296, Folder 5)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Millis, Walter [1/2], 1965-1966 (Box 296, Folder 6)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Millis, Walter [2/2], undated (Box 296, Folder 7)
    - Roof Articles - General correspondence, P, 1963-1964 (Box 297, Folder 1)
    - Roof Articles - General correspondence, P-R, 1962-1963 (Box 297, Folder 2)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Preece, Warren [1/3], 1966 (Box 297, Folder 3)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Preece, Warren [2/3], 1966 (Box 297, Folder 4)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Preece, Warren [3/3], 1963-1968 (Box 297, Folder 5)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Roll, Eric - "Economic Order," 1963-1966 (Box 297, Folder 6)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Roll, Eric - "Economic Order" - Part Three, 1967 (Box 298, Folder 1)
    - Roof Articles - General correspondence, S, 1960-1966 (Box 298, Folder 2)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Smith, Page - History, 1964-1965 (Box 298, Folder 3)
    - Roof Articles - General correspondence, T, 1961-1964 (Box 298, Folder 4)
    - Roof Articles - General correspondence, U-Z, 1961-1964 (Box 298, Folder 5)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Wheeler, Harvey - "Political Order" [1/3], 1966 (Box 298, Folder 6)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Wheeler, Harvey - "Political Order" [2/3], 1966 (Box 298, Folder 7)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Wheeler, Harvey - "Political Order" [3/3], 1966 (Box 298, Folder 8)
    - Roof Articles - Contributions - Wheeler, Harvey - "Political Order" - Comments, 1961-1966 (Box 299, Folder 1)
    - Havet, Jacques - Report on Encyclopædias [1/2], 1966 (Box 299, Folder 2)
    - Havet, Jacques - Report on Encyclopædias [2/2], 1966 (Box 299, Folder 3)
    - Part One - Matter and Energy: Particles to Galaxies - Outline, June 1967 (Box 299, Folder 4)
    - Part One - Matter and Energy - Volume 1 - Outline, June 1968 (Box 299, Folder 5)
    - Part One - Matter and Energy - Volume 2 - Outline, June 1968 (Box 299, Folder 6)
    - Proposed articulation for Parts Two, Five, Six, and Nine, 1967 (Box 299, Folder 7)
    - Proposed articulation for Parts Four, Five, and Nine, September 1967 (Box 299, Folder 8)
    - Part Two - The Earth and its Development - Outline, June 1968 (Box 299, Folder 9)
    - Part Three - Life on Earth: From Virus to Vertebrate - Outline, June 1967 (Box 300, Folder 1)
    - Part Three - Life on Earth: From Virus to Vertebrate - Volume 1 - Outline, June 1968 (Box 300, Folder 2)
    - Part Three - Life on Earth: From Virus to Vertebrate - Volume 2 - Outline, June 1968 (Box 300, Folder 3)
    - Part Four - Human Life - Outline, June 1967 (Box 300, Folder 4)
    - Part Four - Human Life - Volume 1 - Outline, June 1968 (Box 300, Folder 5)
    - Part Four - Human Life - Volume 2 - Outline, June 1968 (Box 300, Folder 6)
    - Proposed articulation for Part Five, Divisions II and IV, September 1967 (Box 300, Folder 7)
    - Part Five - Human Society - Volume 1 - Outline, June 1967 (Box 300, Folder 8)
    - Part Five - Human Society - Volume 2 - Outline, June 1967 (Box 300, Folder 9)
    - Part Five - Human Society - Division IV, The Domain of Law - Proposed Articulation, September 1967 (Box 300, Folder 10)
    - Part Five - Human Society - Volume 1 - Outline, June 1968 (Box 300, Folder 11)
    - Part Five - Human Society - Volume 2 - Outline, June 1968 (Box 301, Folder 1)
    - Part Six - The Arts - Outline, June 1967 (Box 301, Folder 2)
    - Part Six - The Arts - Volume 1 - Outline, June 1968 (Box 301, Folder 3)
    - Part Six - The Arts - Volume 2 - Outline, June 1968 (Box 301, Folder 4)
    - Part Seven - Technology: Techniques and the Applications of Science - Outline, June 1967 (Box 301, Folder 5)
    - Part Seven - Technology - Volume 1 - Outline, June 1968 (Box 301, Folder 6)
    - Part Seven - Technology - Volume 2 - Outline, June 1968 (Box 301, Folder 7)
    - Part Eight - Religion and the Religions of Mankind - Outline, June 1967 (Box 301, Folder 8)
    - Part Eight - Religion and the Religions of Mankind - Volume 1 - Outline, June 1968 (Box 301, Folder 9)
    - Part Eight - Religion and the Religions of Mankind - Volume 2 - Outline, June 1968 (Box 301, Folder 10)
- Series VII: Commission on Freedom of the Press
  Series VII contains correspondence, memoranda, reports, meeting materials, and clippings pertaining to Hutchins' chairmanship of the Commission on Freedom of the Press. The Commission on Freedom of the Press was appointed in 1944 to investigate the freedom, function, and responsibilities of the major agencies of mass communication operative at the time. The Commission was funded by grants from Time, Inc., and Encyclopaedia Britannica, Inc. Materials in this series are arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence and recording of telephone conversation with Mr. H.R. Luce (New York) about Freedom of the Press Committee, November 23, 1943 (Reformatted 2013), 1943-1944 (Box 301, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1943-1945 (Box 301, Folder 12)
  - Memoranda, reports, meeting materials, 1943-1945 (Box 302, Folder 1)
  - Meeting minutes, correspondence, drafts of "General Report," 1943-1946 (Box 302, Folder 2)
  - Financial correspondence, 1943-1947 (Box 302, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 302, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 302, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Durka, William, 1944 (Box 302, Folder 6)
  - Administration, governance, and budget, 1944 (Box 302, Folder 7)
  - Memoranda, meeting minutes, 1944 (Box 302, Folder 8)
  - "General Report" - Outlines and drafts, 1944 (Box 302, Folder 9)
  - Statements, abstract, meeting materials, reports, article draft, 1944-1945 (Box 303, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1944-1946 (Box 303, Folder 2)
  - "Freedom of the Films," circa 1945 (Box 303, Folder 3)
  - Index of documents, circa 1945 (Box 303, Folder 4)
  - Memoranda, chapter proposals, outline, reports, 1945 (Box 303, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, January-June 1946 (Box 303, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, July-December 1946 (Box 303, Folder 7)
  - Reports, 1946 (Box 303, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, reports, reprints, 1946 (Box 304, Folder 1)
  - "General Report" and suggested revisions, "Summary Outline of Principles," 1946 (Box 304, Folder 2)
  - "Government and Mass Communication," Zechariah Chafee, Jr., 1946 (Box 304, Folder 3)
  - "Freedom for the Movies," Ruth A. Inglis, 1946 (Box 304, Folder 4)
  - "General Report," Robert D. Leigh, and revisions, 1946 (Box 304, Folder 5)
  - Reports, comments, revisions, and meeting agenda, 1946 (Box 304, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, off-prints, 1947 (Box 305, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and clippings, 1947 (Box 305, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 305, Folder 3)
  - "The American Radio," Llewellyn White [1/2], 1947 (Box 305, Folder 4)
  - "The American Radio," Llewellyn White [2/2], 1947 (Box 305, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, clippings, reports, off-prints, 1948-1950 (Box 305, Folder 6)
  - Hutchins Commission Report, 1962-1968 (Box 305, Folder 7)
  - "Freedom of the Press: A Framework of Principle for Today and Tomorrow," undated (Box 305, Folder 8)
  - "General Report" - Chapters IV, V, VI - Drafts, undated (Box 306, Folder 1)
- Series VIII: Committee to Frame a World Constitution
  Series VIII contains material relevant to Robert Maynard Hutchins' work with the Committee to Frame a World Constitution, which he helped to form. The Committee to Frame a World Constitution was first convened in the fall of 1945 as part of the post-World War II World Federalist movement. This series includes correspondence, memoranda, reports, drafts, clippings, and other ephemera. Materials are arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, September-December 1945 (Box 306, Folder 2)
  - Memoranda and reports, 1945 (Box 306, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 306, Folder 4)
  - Memoranda, drafts of World Constitution and comments, correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 306, Folder 5)
  - Financial correspondence, 1945-1951 (Box 306, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and reports, 1946 (Box 306, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and clippings, 1946 (Box 306, Folder 8)
  - Memoranda and reports, 1946 (Box 307, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and meeting materials, January-June 1946 (Box 307, Folder 2)